Well, hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 12.
We are going to solve the time complexity of the function print high.
So in this function, we have print high taking into a parking meter that entré A and a B, and we have
three loops and they are nested and we are going to print high in that key loop.
I need from you to think about this algorithm.
Please post the video and write down the solution, try to solve this question because solving exercises
is very important.
So I think and I hope you get the correct questions answer.
We start.
The print high, so we don't care about the Hatter.
We take care about the loop here.
We have the first loop starting.
As I told you, we get the initial conditions that stopping condition and their behavior and how the
increment of that iteration works.
It is A-plus plus, so we are going to go through all the elements from zero to array a length.
OK, so the first loop, the outer loop will go through from all elements from zero to a I denote a
by the array a length.
OK.
And we are going to go through all the elements, so it is of a.
No, in the inner loop, inner loop.
It is here.
This will go through all elements from Jay Equal to zero to Jay to Jay less than be the length.
And the way of increment is G Plus Plus, okay, so B is the array, b the length.
We have solved this in the previous exercise.
OK.
And I told you the trick in that question and exercise number 11 is is understanding that array a that
length is different than array B, the length.
OK.
If they are equal, they would be of a square.
And we have here another loop.
Cold, OK.
This is the the loop.
OK.
It starts from K equal to zero.
To OK, less than 100, 100 thousand.
And the way of increment of gay is plus plus.
So it's going to loop through all the all the elements from zero to 1000 to 100000 loop or iteration.
And we are going to print it as of one, if we calculate how many times this high or this statement
would be executed and displaying high when we result in.
We start from one.
Times how many times this statement would be executed if we executed the 4K loop?
The 4K.
Times 100 times.
OK.
Times how many times the globe would be executed, it depends on the array, be length.
OK, so times b times how many times this J loop would be executed according to the eye condition,
and I will stop at a rate a good length.
So array edit length, it will go through from zero to a and it would be executed eight times.
OK, so the final result would be one thousand one hundred thousand.
B times A.
A high message.
OK.
Or displaying her, OK?
Therefore.
We have 100000 B times A if B equal to one and equal to one, it would be executed 100000 if be equal
to 10 and equal to one.
It would be executed one millionth time.
So we depend on executing this on the value of B and A but but this is a war on terror and in big own
notation.
We don't care about the constant.
We don't care about the constant that is is multiplied by the by the input, by the variable input.
The variable input here is the array, the length and array b the length, but 100000 is a constant.
And we know every time that it would be executed 100000 we could, since it is a high number, but it
is a constant.
We don't care about it.
We care about only studying B times a because this is the variable this is depends on the at.
They are a length and array b length.
OK.
Therefore, the final result and the solution would be all of a times B.
This is the time.